<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens weblog</title>
  <subtitle>A weblog by ldstephens.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/" />
  <updated>2025-11-28T11:56:28Z</updated>
  <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name>ldstephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Media</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/social-media/" />
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/social-media/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July 24, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, let&#39;s talk social media. It&#39;s been around forever, and you know what? I gotta confess, I&#39;ve never been a huge fan. Facebook, Instagram, TikTok, Snapchat – I’ve never had an account on any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closest I came was Twitter. Used to have it on and off, mainly to keep up with current events. But after that whole thing with the shitposter buying XTwitter I said fuck this and deleted my account for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I&#39;ve been on Mastodon. It&#39;s a different platform, but honestly? Here&#39;s the thing: everyone I follow there also has a blog with an RSS feed that follow. And guess what? The stuff I see on Mastodon is the same stuff I’ve already seen in those feeds. There&#39;s some occasional back-and-forth but for conversations I much prefer email. You can always reach me through my blog if you ever want to chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after a lot of thinking, I&#39;ve decided to ditch Mastodon too. Social media, just ain&#39;t my thing. I&#39;ll still be here on the blog, creating and sharing my thoughts. Just minus the social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Advice on Blogging</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/advice-on-blogging/" />
    <updated>2024-07-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/advice-on-blogging/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July 27, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2023/advice-on-blogging/&quot;&gt;Jim Nielsen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What my blog is now is a result of me wrestling with what it even means to blog. What I love about “blogging” is how personal it is. Even the word, “blog”, doesn’t give you any classifying genre of what content or experience you’ll get from any one individual’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is all about personal expression. The best part? You never know what you&#39;ll get from someone&#39;s blog, making each one a unique discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RSS Versus Bookmarks</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/rss-versus-bookmarks/" />
    <updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/rss-versus-bookmarks/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 03, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally I read two blog posts about RSS within days of each other this week. Chris is emphasizing the benefits of RSS and encouraging folks to start using it while Jason has decided to stop using it. So I thought I would chime in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughts.uncountable.uk/request-for-iphone-rss-help/&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request for iPhone RSS help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually prefer if &lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughts.uncountable.uk/id-rather-you-didnt-read-this/&quot;&gt;you read my blog over RSS&lt;/a&gt; than the web, for two reasons. Firstly, you have more chance of seeing my future posts that way, rather than remembering to visit the website again. But secondly, and more importantly, I think you will have an improved digital life if you incorporate RSS into your daily habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jasonjournals.com/posts/no-need-for-feeds&quot;&gt;Jason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Need For Feeds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to try something old-school, relatively “low-tech” and “slow-tech.” I deleted my RSS Reader app (NetNewsWire) from all my devices. And I have no web bookmarks to Feedly. But how would I keep up with the latest? What about the cool sites I follow? Answer: &lt;em&gt;surf the web!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I simply rely on my browser’s &lt;strong&gt;bookmarks&lt;/strong&gt;. I made a folder called, “RSS Replacement” and saved all the sites that I like to visit for new articles. So I more &lt;em&gt;intentionally&lt;/em&gt; go to my bookmark folder and click those I want to visit when I think to do so. I no longer feel pulled to frequently check an app — pull to refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I appreciate Jason&#39;s reasoning for deciding to stop using RSS but I side with Chris on this. I have been using RSS for as long as I can remember. Here&#39;s why: using RSS centralizes my favorite blogs and news sites, all in one place. I get real-time updates and I never miss a post from my favorite bloggers. Without RSS there is little chance that I would have ever seen the blog post above written by Chris and Jason.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blogging Challenges - Are They Really Worth It?</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/blogging-challenges-are-they-really-worth-it/" />
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/blogging-challenges-are-they-really-worth-it/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 13, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an indie blogger, our unique voice is our biggest asset. Blogging challenges, especially those requiring daily posts, often lead to low-quality content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer reading spontaneous posts that are authentic, not those written solely to meet a daily challenge goal. As a reader, I can easily tell the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write when you have something genuine to share, rather than forcing content to meet a challenge deadline. Just my opinion!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blogging - Eliminating Distractions</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/blogging-eliminating-distractions/" />
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/blogging-eliminating-distractions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 17, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Lionel &amp;quot;Ploum&amp;quot; Dricot &lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com/pb-ploum&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; about his blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://peopleandblogs.com/&quot;&gt;People and Blogs&lt;/a&gt;with Manu Moreale:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is exactly where I want it to be. If I had to start again, I would simply do it like I did in 2022. I was quick to remove any form of comments from my blog and, later, any kind of statistics. As far as I know, I’m one of the few strong advocates for the complete removal of statistics/analytic/tracking tools. It’s not ethical to spy on users but it is also completely counterproductive. Statistics on websites are a brainworm. People are obsessed by it and it makes them write dumb stuff in order to increase a dumb counter. Getting rid of any audience-measuring tool is one of the best things I did in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve completely deleted all my social network accounts and never felt so free. Ironically, the less I was using social networks, the more readers I had on my blog. Social networks don’t bring you an audience. This is a lie! Social networks distract you from your real work and prevent your audience from reaching you. That’s their whole business! I know how frightening it is to delete permanently an account with thousands of followers. But this number is also a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote has prompted me to rethink my approach to this blog. While I’ve always valued the freedom to write what I want, the reminder to eliminate distractions like analytics and social media has hit home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve turned off analytics to focus more on the writing. I&#39;ve also eliminated social media letting my blog stand on its own merits. This feels like a step toward a better connection with my work and readers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>15 blogging rules</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/15-blogging-rules/" />
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/15-blogging-rules/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;September 3, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give up on trying to be popular. I try not to filter myself based on what I believe will be popular. Some of my favourite posts get ignored. Some posts get popular and I have no idea why. Besides, terrible posts get buried fast if I’m posting three times a week. So post with abandon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give up on trying to be interesting. Readers will come to my site for what’s interesting to me, or not, it’s fine, just say what I think about whatever I’m thinking about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://interconnected.org/home/2020/09/10/streak&quot;&gt;Matt Webb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Who am I responsible to here?</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/who-am-i-responsible-to-here/" />
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/who-am-i-responsible-to-here/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;September 3, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Whenever I change blogging platforms or domain names or simply post to several places, I feel a twinge of guilt. How will my “audience” feel about the changes? Does it confuse things?[…] I don’t get a lot of traffic, but it’s also not zero traffic, so I feel some responsibility. But why? I am not writing for money or influence or popularity. I write to better understand what I’m thinking about, and sometimes share the result. I write so that I have a record of those things. I write, almost entirely, for me.[…] In that light, I shouldn’t need to worry about whether my RSS feed is consistent or if people need to follow me in too many places. I don’t want to be a dick about it, but c’mon, it’s an unimportant personal blog by some nobody on the internet. Let’s not overthink it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baty.net/2024/07/who-am-i-responsible-to-here/&quot;&gt;Jack Baty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Write Like You Talk</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/write-like-you-talk/" />
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/write-like-you-talk/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;September 3, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Here&#39;s a simple trick for getting more people to read what you write: write in spoken language.[…] It seems to be hard for most people to write in spoken language. So perhaps the best solution is to write your first draft the way you usually would, then afterward look at each sentence and ask &amp;quot;Is this the way I&#39;d say this if I were talking to a friend?&amp;quot; If it isn&#39;t, imagine what you would say, and use that instead. After a while this filter will start to operate as you write. When you write something you wouldn&#39;t say, you&#39;ll hear the clank as it hits the page.[…] just don&#39;t let a sentence through unless it&#39;s the way you&#39;d say it to a friend.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://paulgraham.com/talk.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - On personal websites and social web</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/re-on-personal-websites-and-social-web/" />
    <updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/re-on-personal-websites-and-social-web/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;September 23, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com/on-personal-websites-and-social-web&quot;&gt;Manu reflects&lt;/a&gt; on the divide between two groups regarding the future of being social on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in those posts, I’m starting to see a trend of some sort. People are apparently starting to split into two camps that follow two very different ideological approaches when it comes to being social on the web. And when I say “people” I mean tech people, those who care about this type of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other you have the people who are realising that maybe the solution is not to recreate social media but rather to abandon it and go back to a more deliberate way to be social online, using personal sites, small forums, emails, and other “traditional” tools. I’m obviously part of this second group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that I’m hopeful. I do think people are slowly starting to realise that you can get immense human value from the web outside of traditional social media. You have to work for it but it’s absolutely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I side with Manu on this. Social Media is shit (my opinion). I’ve mentioned many times in the past that I’ve never had an account with any social media platforms that most people participate in, except for Twitter and Mastodon, both of which I’ve stopped using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I’ve discovered indie blogging and indie blogs. I have over 100 in my RSS feed, and I add a few new ones every week. I find that indie blogging provides a better, more authentic experience than social media by offering thoughtful content without the distractions of ads and algorithms. Instead of chasing likes or viral trends, indie bloggers write with passion, giving readers deeper insights and unique perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, blogs create a more meaningful community where discussions feel genuine and less fleeting compared to social media’s fast-paced, superficial interactions. Bloggers also have full control over their content, free from the ever-changing algorithms that often limit visibility on social platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - How I find interesting blogs</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/re-how-i-find-interesting-blogs/" />
    <updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/re-how-i-find-interesting-blogs/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;September 30, 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this conversation so I thought I would chime in: it revolves around how different bloggers discover new blogs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.bjhess.com/2024/09/13/i-appreciate-personal.html&quot;&gt;Barry Hess&lt;/a&gt; mentions submitting his blog to various directories but notes limited traffic from them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jrn.sh/post/how-i-find-interesting-blogs&quot;&gt;JRN&lt;/a&gt;responds, saying they prefer discovering blogs through bloggers linking to or responding to each other, social platforms like Mastodon, and blog exploration features on platforms like Micro.blog. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughts.uncountable.uk/re-how-i-find-interesting-blogs/&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; at “uncountable thoughts” echoes JRN’s sentiment, emphasizing that blog directories aren’t heavily used for discovery; instead, contextual cross-linking between blogs is a more effective method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m relatively new to the indie blogging, so I’m always on the lookout for new blogs to follow. What works best for me is when I come across a blog that references another one I almost always click through, check out the “About” page, and skim the article archives to see if their content interests me. If it does, I’ll add their blog to my RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if you’ve stumbled upon this blog post, you have the chance to discover three new blogs, in addition to mine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bjhess.com/&quot;&gt;Barry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jrn.sh/&quot;&gt;JRN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughts.uncountable.uk/&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Don&#39;t Make a Blog, Make a Brain Dump</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-dont-make-a-blog-make-a-brain-dump/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-dont-make-a-blog-make-a-brain-dump/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 2, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://btxx.org/posts/dump/#menu&quot;&gt;Bradley Taunt, btxx.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem arises when you finally do convince someone to start “blogging” online; self-doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What could I possibly have to share?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What if everyone hates what I post?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What if my content sucks?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just dump it. Who cares. It’s the internet after all, so who are you trying to impress? The point is that your sharing your own experiences that are unique to you as an individual. Posting something that you think is pointless or mundane might be extremely helpful or, at the very least, entertaining for someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write up what you did over the weekend, a new recipe you tried out, review a movie/book or video game you enjoyed, list step-by-step instructions on how you installed a new appliance in your house - anything! Just write and be part of what made the internet fun, exciting and personal again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“Unplatform” a guidebook for escaping social media</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/unplatform-a-guidebook-for-escaping-social-media/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/unplatform-a-guidebook-for-escaping-social-media/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 2, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unplatform.fromthesuperhighway.com/&quot;&gt;Unplatform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unplatform is an interactive guidebook, online library, and recommendations database intended to help you escape social media and join the indie web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not on social media, but I’m a big fan of having your own space on the indie web. If you’re thinking about quitting social media, this guidebook is definitely worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How I use AI for writing and coding</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/how-i-use-ai-for-writing-and-coding/" />
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/how-i-use-ai-for-writing-and-coding/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 6, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using AI in two ways: for help with my writing and for figuring out how to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My writing skills aren’t that great. I know what I want to say and how I want to say it, but I struggle to put it into words. So, I use AI to proofread and improve the structure of what I’ve written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way AI helps me is with writing HTML and CSS for my static blog projects. I use it to explain things in HTML or CSS and to offer the code. For example, yesterday, I had a couple of posts where I kept getting an error in my HTML, and I couldn’t figure out what was wrong. So, I copied the code and put it into Claude. It rewrote the code and explained what it fixed. I guess you could call that debugging my code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI has become a valuable tool for me. Whether it’s helping me improve my writing or troubleshooting code, it saves me time and makes things easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - No, The People Didn’t Vote For This</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/re-no-the-people-didnt-vote-for-this/" />
    <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/re-no-the-people-didnt-vote-for-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 10, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democrats, obviously, aren’t thrilled, but the more meaningful data is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/5129353-gop-support-for-musk-influence-with-trump-falls-dramatically-poll/&quot;&gt;Republicans don’t like what Elon Musk is doing&lt;/a&gt; at all.[…] Voters who supported Trump based on economic promises are instead seeing federal support for their local hospitals vanish, government contracts that supported thousands of local jobs disappear, and consumer prices continue to rise. The very voters who wanted economic stability are getting the opposite: economic chaos driven by an unelected billionaire’s personal agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/2025/02/10/no-the-people-didnt-vote-for-this/&quot;&gt;Mike Masnick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well! Well! Well! Lied to!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Tracy Durnell</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-tracy-durnell/" />
    <updated>2025-02-20T17:23:08Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-tracy-durnell/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 20, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employ private posts — I don’t have to publish everything I write&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tracydurnell.com/2025/01/21/guiding-principles-for-my-website/&quot;&gt;Tracy Durnell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kindle Paperwhite’s annoying flashes</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/kindle-paperwhites-annoying-flashes/" />
    <updated>2025-02-20T22:11:49Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/kindle-paperwhites-annoying-flashes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 20, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nice-marmot.net/Archives/2025/February_2025.html#note_2766&quot;&gt;Dave Rogers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a 10th generation Kindle Paperwhite. I&#39;ve read from it a fair amount, particularly when I was away, because it&#39;s so light. But I generally don&#39;t care for the experience. It&#39;s very slow, and whenever I turn a page I get this annoying flash as the screen goes through this inversion process from whatever mode I&#39;m in until it settles on either the Dark or Light Mode, which I selected. That is, if I&#39;m in Light Mode, the page will first appear in Dark Mode, then switch to Light Mode. If I&#39;m in Dark Mode and turn the page, the page first appears in Light Mode, then switches to dark. Very annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a Paperwhite that I use for reading, and while I appreciate its lightweight, I’m not a huge fan of the overall experience either. I continue to use it because it’s so lightweight. I have an iPad, but it’s simply too heavy for comfortable reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m actually reading a physical book for the first time in a very long time, and I’m enjoying the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Platforms own you, not vice versa</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/platforms-own-you-not-vice-versa/" />
    <updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/platforms-own-you-not-vice-versa/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February 26, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/02/25/chegg-google-ai-lawsuit/&quot;&gt;Hannah Ziegler&lt;/a&gt;, The Washington Post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online education company Chegg sues Google, says AI is killing business A new lawsuit against Google alleges that the search giant’s artificial intelligence summaries have hurt online education company Chegg’s traffic and revenue so much that the company may not survive in its current form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chegg, which provides students with homework help and test answers, filed the suit against Google and parent company Alphabet this week in federal court. In its quarterly report released Monday, the company tied its recent financial struggles to AI-generated search summaries and claimed Google has “unjustly retained traffic” that once flowed to Chegg’s site. Chegg reported $144 million in revenue in its fourth quarter, a 24 percent decrease from the same period last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chegg&#39;s pissed because Google isn&#39;t sending them traffic any more. Welcome to the club. If your business relies on another company&#39;s platform, you&#39;re a tenant with no lease. Chegg&#39;s lawsuit? Probably a long shot. The lesson? The landlord can do whatever the hell they want and a public company like Chegg should know better than to rely on someone else’s platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why write when no one’s reading?</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/why-write-when-no-ones-reading/" />
    <updated>2025-03-02T15:06:59Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/why-write-when-no-ones-reading/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;March 2, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing without an audience might feel pointless. It isn’t just about being read; it’s about thinking more clearly. Putting thoughts into words forces us to process them in a way passive consumption doesn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But most of all, write because your voice matters even if only to you. And if just one person finds what you write useful, then that makes it even more worthwhile. I think about the things I’ve read that have stuck with me, and I hope my words can do the same for someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Zsolt Benke</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-zsolt-benke/" />
    <updated>2025-03-07T10:03:21Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-zsolt-benke/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;March 7, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;getting recognized as a blogger these days is rarely going to work. People are increasingly consuming different types of content these days, and this is largely due to the way AI is changing the way we interact with the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, having a blog for thinking out loud is still the best way to learn and then “report” it, even if we’re the only ones reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://decoding.io/2025/02/read-its-still-worth-blogging-in-the-age-of-ai/&quot;&gt;Zsolt Benke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Barry Hess</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-barry-hess/" />
    <updated>2025-03-16T11:31:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-barry-hess/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;March 16, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is a conversation. It’s a conversation with yourself and it’s a conversation with others.[…] You don’t have to be an essayist. (Though you can be one if you want!) Don’t let those essayists discourage you from blogging. Just write. Just blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bjhess.com/posts/you-re-a-blogger-not-an-essayist&quot;&gt;Barry Hess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This makes my fucking blood boil!</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/this-makes-my-fucking-blood-boil/" />
    <updated>2025-03-22T10:15:28Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/this-makes-my-fucking-blood-boil/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;March 22, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Peck,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/21/social-security-lutnick-doge-checks&quot;&gt; writing for Axios&lt;/a&gt;: Seniors won&#39;t complain if they miss a Social Security check, Lutnick says&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commerce secretary Howard Lutnick suggested this week that only &amp;quot;fraudsters&amp;quot; would complain about missing a monthly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/20/doge-social-security-deposit-fraud&quot;&gt;Social Security&lt;/a&gt; check, and that most people wouldn&#39;t mind if the government simply skipped a payment.[…] More than 70 million Americans get a Social Security benefit every month, and for many, those checks are their only income.[…] &amp;quot;Let&#39;s say Social Security didn&#39;t send out their checks this month. My mother-in-law, who&#39;s 94, she wouldn&#39;t call and complain,&amp;quot; Lutnick — a billionaire former Wall Street CEO — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=182ckTL2KBA&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; the billionaire &amp;quot;All In&amp;quot; podcast host Chamath Palihapitiya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of shit just makes my fucking blood boil. As many of you know you know I’m 80 years old. I depend on my monthly Social Security check to live. Would I miss a check? Hell yes! So would millions of other seniors Republicans, Democrats, Independents, and those who don’t give a shit about politics. For some, it’s their &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; source of income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not like we’re getting a freebie here. We all paid into Social Security and Medicare our entire working lives. I started working when I was 15 years old and was never without a job until I retired. So I paid my fucking dues and so did all other seniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but sure, let&#39;s just skip a payment, what could possibly go wrong? Maybe Lutnick thinks we can all just hop on our yachts and ride out the month, or maybe we should start selling off our prescription meds to make rent. The sheer arrogance of a billionaire pretending he knows what it&#39;s like to rely on Social Security is bullshit. News flash: We&#39;re not asking for a favor. We&#39;re demanding what we &lt;em&gt;earned&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can tell I’m pissed. &lt;em&gt;Don’t fuck with our Social Security and Medicare!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Jack Baty</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-jack-baty/" />
    <updated>2025-04-16T11:30:36Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-jack-baty/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baty.net/journal/2025/04/04/today/&quot;&gt;Jack Baty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to find a way for my brain to relax. I spend entire days with a dozen apps open, each with a dozen tabs open. I click rapidly between them looking for something to focus on. I never find anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baty.net/posts/2025/04/i-dont-care-what-you-think/&quot;&gt;Jack Baty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean to be rude, but I don’t care much what you think. OK, that’s not exactly true, &lt;strong&gt;I care deeply what you think&lt;/strong&gt;. Maybe it’s more accurate to say that I don’t &lt;em&gt;worry&lt;/em&gt; about what you think. Are you mad that I keep switching platforms? Sorry, not sorry. Are you annoyed that I use words like “just” and “maybe” and “really” too often? Yeah, me too. We’ll get over it. Does it bother you that I don’t do enough throat-clearing before mentioning something that has become problematic? You’ll be fine. Would you prefer that I only write about Emacs? Not happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There, I feel a little better now, because when I got up this morning I wanted to apologize for being alive and just (see, there’s that word again) shut everything down. I don’t think I’ll do that, though, because regardless of what you think…&lt;em&gt;I think&lt;/em&gt;…and it needs to come out somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get a kick out of Jack.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Juha-Matti Santala</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-juha-matti-santala/" />
    <updated>2025-04-17T15:39:20Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-juha-matti-santala/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 17, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess for us techies especially, the desire to tinker with the site comes from having a deeper interest in writing code than writing prose.[…] I also love tinkering with my website to learn new things and to make the site and its tooling even better suited for my own needs.[…] I can write my blog posts on my iPad when I’m in the library or local pub and at that time, there’s no way for me to tinker with the tools or the website itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/resisting-the-urge-to-rewrite-the-website/&quot;&gt;Juha-Matti Santala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Text editors</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/text-editors/" />
    <updated>2025-04-19T17:28:40Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/text-editors/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 19, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m tinkering with editors to write blog posts that integrate with my 11ty site. Posts need front matter and must be in Markdown, so the editor has to load my 11ty project and let me drop new posts into the right folder. It also needs to play nice with GitHub Desktop. Since I’m not coding anymore,just writing Markdown, I don’t need anything fancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’ve only got two editors installed that do the job: BBEdit and VS Code. I’ve tried writing Markdown in VS Code, but honestly, it’s a shitty experience. I also gave Sublime Text a shot, but it takes too much setup and learning, and it’s $99. Not worth it for me. So for now, I’m sticking with BBEdit.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The future of the iPad</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/the-future-of-the-ipad/" />
    <updated>2025-04-21T17:42:15Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/the-future-of-the-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 21, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some quick thoughts on the future of the iPad. Since the iPad launched in 2010, it&#39;s been the go-to device for kids. It&#39;s safe, simple, great for games, learning, and videos. These &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parents.com/what-are-ipad-kids-8692488&quot;&gt;iPad kids&lt;/a&gt; have grown up with it as their first computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2023/04/tablets-more-common-in-households-with-children.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot;&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; that a significant portion of iPad users are kids and families. Around 80% of U.S. households with children own tablets, including iPads. This high rate of ownership shows that tablets are popular among families with kids under 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happens when those iPad kids become adults? The oldest are maybe 15 now. We don&#39;t know what they&#39;ll choose as adults. Maybe they&#39;ll stick with the iPad because it&#39;s the computer they know. For them, simplicity isn&#39;t a drawback, it&#39;s how computers work. That&#39;s the open question that will shape the future of the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think the future of the iPad will be determined by those who started on the Mac, went iPad, and are now going back to the Mac after hitting iPadOS limitations and want Mac like features. I think the iPads future will be determined by those kids who have grown up using an iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New desk chair</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/new-desk-chair/" />
    <updated>2025-04-26T11:38:15Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/new-desk-chair/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 26, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My old chair was plastic, and the left support piece that connects the back to the seat broke. I lived with it for a couple of months because I was too lazy to look for a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I finally decided to get off my ass and get a replacement. I knew what I wanted and asked ChatGPT for recommendations. One of the suggestions was the Kroy Ergonomic Mesh Swivel Task Chair, Black (UN59456) from Staples. My local store had it in stock, so I hopped in my truck and picked it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new chair offers an extra two inches of height compared to my old one. Now my hands sit slightly above the keyboard instead of below it. It&#39;s way more comfortable and much better for typing. It’s a fantastic improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post - You should blog</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-you-should-blog/" />
    <updated>2025-04-26T15:28:18Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-you-should-blog/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 26, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some advice if you’re starting a blog for the first time (or it’s been awhile):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share your thoughts on &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt;. You’re a blogger, not an opinion columnist
in the washington post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your mind! Write about why you changed your mind!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write however you want. Run-on sentences. Weird grammar. Write in limericks,
sonnets, or haikus – defy the grammar cops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keith.is/blog/you-should-blog/#:~:text=Some%20advice%20if,the%20grammar%20cops.&quot;&gt;Keith Kurson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link post - An investment in your health…</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-an-investment-in-your-health/" />
    <updated>2025-04-28T15:28:34Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-an-investment-in-your-health/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April 28, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patrickrhone.net/an-investment-in-your-health/&quot;&gt;Patrick Rhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But your body, once it’s done, it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it’s even more important to use and maintain it as well as you can, for as long as you can. Because it’s irreplaceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, put the best fuel (food) in it you can. Make sure that fuel is clean and high-quality (organic, sustainable, balanced, chemical free, ingredients you can trust, etc.). Keep your regularly scheduled maintenance visits (doctors, dentist, etc.). Run it regularly at both cruising and highway speeds (regular walking and exercise). Give it regular washings and keep it looking good (clean cars run better and last longer, so do bodies). These things may cost you more, but that’s because they are better and better for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent advice!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Search</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/search-2025-05-31/" />
    <updated>2025-05-31T14:39:59Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/search-2025-05-31/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;May 31, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, when I&#39;m looking for an answer or doing research, I rarely use Google anymore. I&#39;ve been using ChatGPT instead. Depending on what I&#39;m after, it can take forever to dig through Google results to find what I need. ChatGPT just gets to the point. ChatGPT also learns about me. It knows I use Netlify, so when I ask a question about it, I don&#39;t have to explain much, it just knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, there are privacy concerns. But let&#39;s be honest, Google has been collecting our data for years. I do what I can to protect my privacy, but it&#39;s already out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get that some folks are wary of AI, but it&#39;s not going anywhere. We might as well lean into it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Post: RFK Jr.’s CDC Panel Ditches Some Flu Shots Based on Anti-Vaccine Junk Data</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-rfk-jrs-cdc-panel-ditches-some-flu-shots-based-on-anti-vaccine-junk-data/" />
    <updated>2025-06-28T11:46:03Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-rfk-jrs-cdc-panel-ditches-some-flu-shots-based-on-anti-vaccine-junk-data/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;June 28, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2025/06/27/rfk-cdc-ditch-flu-shots-based-on-junk-data&quot;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an ignorant conspiracy nut lead the Department of Health and Human Services is angering and worrisome, to say the least. But it’s also incredibly frustrating, because Donald Trump himself isn’t an anti-vaxxer. In fact, one of the few great achievements of the first Trump Administration was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Warp_Speed&quot;&gt;Operation Warp Speed&lt;/a&gt;, a highly successful effort spearheaded by the US federal government to “facilitate and accelerate the development, manufacturing, and distribution of COVID-19 vaccines, therapeutics, and diagnostics.” […] But instead, while plotting his return to office, Trump smelled opportunity with the anti-vax contingent &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2025/06/27/trump-stupid-americans&quot;&gt;of the out-and-proud Stupid-Americans&lt;/a&gt;, and now here we are, with a genuine know-nothing lunatic like RFK Jr. as Secretary of Health and Human Services. God help us if another pandemic hits in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has me worried. Will I even be able to get my flu and COVID shots this fall? I’m a senior. Seniors&#39; get the high-dose version for extra protection. But sure, let’s gamble with seniors’ lives. What could go wrong? With this fucking whack job running Health and Human Services, America’s about to get a whole lot sicker.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Run-Walk-Run</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/run-walk-run/" />
    <updated>2025-06-30T09:43:08Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/run-walk-run/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;June 30, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&#39;ve started adding some running sections to my morning walks with Trix (our dog), I decided to start recording them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/&quot;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt; yesterday. I&#39;ve had a Strava account for years, from back in my bike racing days, so it was easy to pick it back up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not planning to do anything serious with the running, but hey, at 80, I might actually place pretty well in some 5K events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&#39;d be more into 5K trail runs than road races, though. For now, it&#39;s more about staying fit and healthy, but who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link post: I don’t want your email</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-i-dont-want-your-email/" />
    <updated>2025-07-07T16:18:48Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-i-dont-want-your-email/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July 7, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know who reads this. I don’t know how they find it. I don’t know if they’ll ever come back. I don’t know a damned thing. And that’s by design. I value my privacy and by extension, I value others’. That’s exactly why I don’t have newsletters. The last thing I want is someone’s email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is a place to get things out of my head. I write for myself. Putting it on display provides just enough social pressure to give it &lt;em&gt;that much more&lt;/em&gt; care. But it’d be fine if it was read by no one. I won’t lie–that wasn’t always the case. It took me a lot of years to grind that desire out of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many folks got caught in the trap that they &lt;em&gt;just might&lt;/em&gt; be able to make a living by making content. And just like every other road to fame, 99.9% of them didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll never grow a following or make a dime from this blog. That’s just fine. It keeps things clean and easy. I have a simple site that I pay nothing to host. I have no aspirations beyond what this currently is. I write the things I want to write. People may read it. If they do, awesome. If they don’t, whatever. It’s freeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who cares about how I feel. More importantly, this approach respects readers. They’re not tracked. They’re not bothered with ads. There are no stupid GDPR labyrinths. None of their personal information is stored. They come, they read, they leave. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjonori.blog/posts/i-dont-want-your-email/&quot;&gt;PJ Onori&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always find it enjoyable to read others&#39; perspectives on blogs and blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anti-Vaxx Stupidity: U.S. measles cases hit highest level in 33 years</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/anti-vaxx-stupidity-us-measles-cases-hit-highest-level-in-33-years/" />
    <updated>2025-07-11T16:57:59Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/anti-vaxx-stupidity-us-measles-cases-hit-highest-level-in-33-years/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July 11, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is just fucking GREAT. Measles is making a comeback. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2025/07/09/nx-s1-5461155/measles-outbreak-cdc-vaccination-health&quot;&gt;The U.S. is having its biggest outbreak in 33 years&lt;/a&gt;, with more than a thousand cases and counting, mostly because too many people decided vaccines are optional. “The measles milestone comes the same week that some of the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2025/07/08/nx-s1-5459978/rfk-jr-vaccine-pediatrics-public-health-lawsuit&quot;&gt; nation&#39;s leading medical associations&lt;/a&gt; sued Health Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr., charging him with what they characterize as an effort to undermine trust in vaccines among the American public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texas is leading the charge, and summer travel is helping measles spread across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why Am I Still Listening?</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/why-am-i-still-listening/" />
    <updated>2025-07-19T09:38:46Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/why-am-i-still-listening/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July 19, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a tech podcast that I listen to (not naming names) with three hosts. One of them is a smug, know-it-all asshole who makes the show almost unbearable at times. So why do I keep listening? Well, because the other two are great, and I often learn something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve deleted the podcast from my feed more than once, and I&#39;ll probably do it again. Today&#39;s episode, during my walk, pushed me right back to that point.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fiddling with my blogs today</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/fiddling-with-my-blogs-today/" />
    <updated>2025-07-21T19:09:16Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/fiddling-with-my-blogs-today/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July 21, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fiddling with my blogs today and made a few updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this site, I rebuilt the site using modified version of the 11ty base blog and added a background color. Now both my blogs have the same layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not sure if I&#39;ll link to weblog.ldstephens from ldstephens. There&#39;s already a link going the other way in the nav.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On The Weird Web</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/on-the-weird-web/" />
    <updated>2025-08-03T10:43:51Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/on-the-weird-web/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 3, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m so sick of hyper-specialized, narrowly focused web presence. Give me weird. Give me personal. Talk about more than just “your focus.” I want to hear about music and art and what you’re reading and your hobbies and travels. Show me the real you. Make the web weird again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gomakethings.com/the-weird-web/&quot;&gt;Chris Ferdinandi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lstephens has always been pretty narrowly focused on tech and Apple stuff. That&#39;s exactly why I started this weblog - as a place where I can freely post about everything else. It’s my weird web, and I don&#39;t want to bore my tech followers with personal stories, random thoughts, the occasional rant, or whatever else I&#39;m into that has nothing to do with tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>There’s no fucking cure for stupid</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/theres-no-fucking-cure-for-stupid/" />
    <updated>2025-08-08T13:25:30Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/theres-no-fucking-cure-for-stupid/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 8, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/05/health/rfk-jr-vaccine-funding.html?unlocked_article_code=1.cE8.a0JR.g9jlujYQCzsG&amp;amp;smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;referringSource=articleShare&quot;&gt;RFK Jr. Cancels Nearly $500 Million in mRNA Vaccine Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. has canceled nearly $500 million of grants and contracts for developing mRNA vaccines, the Department of Health and Human Services &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hhs.gov/press-room/hhs-winds-down-mrna-development-under-barda.html&quot;&gt;announced on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the latest blow to research on this technology. In May, the Department of Health and Human Services &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/05/29/health/moderna-trump-bird-flu-vaccine-contract.html&quot;&gt;revoked a nearly $600 million contract&lt;/a&gt; to the drugmaker Moderna to develop a vaccine against bird flu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new cancellations dismayed scientists, many of whom regard mRNA shots as the best option for protecting Americans in a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a bad day for science,” said Scott Hensley, an immunologist at the University of Pennsylvania who has been working to develop an mRNA vaccine against influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Analytics</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/analytics-2025-8-16/" />
    <updated>2025-08-16T11:03:02Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/analytics-2025-8-16/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 16, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytics numbers can be deceiving. They only capture part of your audience, missing readers who follow your site in RSS without ever visiting directly. That means the traffic you see is just the drive-by visitors. Keep that in mind the next time you judge your site&#39;s performance by analytics alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link post: This is your reminder that…</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-this-is-your-reminder-that/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T11:50:43Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/link-post-this-is-your-reminder-that/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 21, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pundits are not Journalists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Op-ed is not news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls are propaganda.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone can be a “media outlet” or a “Journalist” on the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because you read it does not make it true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Especially scrutinize things that confirm your theories and views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust but verify.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patrickrhone.net/15055-2/&quot;&gt;Patrick Rhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quoting Dave Pell</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-dave-pell/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T14:25:43Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/quoting-dave-pell/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 21, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dem Bones:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;Few measurements reflect the luster of a political party’s brand more clearly than the choice by voters to identify with it — whether they register on a clipboard in a supermarket parking lot, at the Department of Motor Vehicles or in the comfort of their own home. And fewer and fewer Americans are choosing to be Democrats.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/20/us/politics/democratic-party-voter-registration-crisis.html?unlocked_article_code=1.fk8.tFTN.oXrlWoASCDq8&amp;amp;smid=bs-share&quot;&gt;The Democratic Party Faces a Voter Registration Crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thou Shall Not:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;A federal judge in Texas temporarily halted on Wednesday a state law that would have required the Ten Commandments to be visibly displayed in every public school classroom by Sept. 1.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/20/us/politics/ten-commandments-texas.html?unlocked_article_code=1.fk8.Ljtu.pJ_vXshqHiWM&amp;amp;smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;referringSource=articleShare&quot;&gt;Judge Halts Texas Law Mandating the Ten Commandments in School&lt;/a&gt;. (Maybe people should spend less time pushing the ten commandments and more time following them.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://managingeditor.substack.com/p/burger-and-the-king&quot;&gt;Dave Pell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Look</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/new-look/" />
    <updated>2025-08-23T10:05:43Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/new-look/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 23, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been tinkering with the site’s design and layout the last couple of days. The new color scheme is my take on &lt;a href=&quot;https://draculatheme.com/&quot;&gt;Dracula&lt;/a&gt; (the theme, not the vampire), and navigation has moved to the footer. I like this version better since it’s mine, unlike the old &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy-base-blog&quot;&gt;11ty-base-blog&lt;/a&gt; setup.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>August 24, 2025, at 3:20:03 PM</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/august-24-2025-at-32003-pm/" />
    <updated>2025-08-24T15:21:18Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/august-24-2025-at-32003-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 24, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made a few more changes to the site today. Moved the navigation from the footer to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Updated design</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/updated-design/" />
    <updated>2025-10-25T17:11:38Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/updated-design/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;October 25, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the design of this site today. It’s simpler, faster, and easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new look sticks to a clean black-and-white theme that automatically switches to dark mode if your device prefers it. Links are always underlined for clarity, and system fonts keep everything feeling native and quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a small refresh — focused on readability and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>October 26, 2025, at 10:34:36 AM</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/october-26-2025-at-103436am/" />
    <updated>2025-10-26T10:38:19Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/october-26-2025-at-103436am/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;October 26, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Happiness is not about having everything you want, but loving what you have.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/29/well/move/102-year-old-yogi-charlotte-chopin.html&quot;&gt;Charlotte Chopin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>October 26, 2025</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/october-26-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-10-26T20:41:02Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/october-26-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;October 26, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10:48:25 AM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been in the 30s the last few mornings here in central New Jersey. We&#39;re close to peak fall color. This afternoon I&#39;m going to mow the grass for what will be the last time until next spring. Of course, I use it along with the leaf blower to clean up all the leaves that are starting to fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2:37:51 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mowed the entire lawn, and the last thing was the trail that goes around the property. Unfortunately, the transmission belt on my Cub Cadet ZT1 zero-turn mower broke about a quarter mile back in the woods. Shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’ll have to tow it out and get it fixed, as it doesn’t look like a repair I can handle myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hobbies</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/hobbies/" />
    <updated>2025-11-01T12:46:27Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/hobbies/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;November 1, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite hobbies is exploring different text editors. They typically fall into two categories: simple and ready-to-use, or deep and endlessly customizable, provided you invest the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors like iA Writer and MarkEdit are user-friendly and come with most of the essential features built-in. In contrast, Drafts, VS Code, BBEdit, and Sublime Text offer extensive customization options, but require a willingness to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drafts is my go-to editor because I&#39;ve used it for years and have customized it to suit my preferences. When I need a more focused writing environment, I use iA Writer. I use VS Code to manage my 11ty sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More design updates</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/more-design-updates/" />
    <updated>2025-11-01T13:13:44Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/more-design-updates/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;November 1, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, I updated the homepage of this site. I&#39;ve been wanting to add my 10 most recent posts to it, and I finally managed to get it done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Practical Path to Universal Healthcare</title>
    <link href="https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/a-practical-path-to-universal-healthcare/" />
    <updated>2025-11-28T11:56:28Z</updated>
    <id>https://weblog.ldstephens.net/posts/a-practical-path-to-universal-healthcare/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been digging into Scott Galloway’s take on healthcare, something he talks about a lot on &lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.voxmedia.com/show/pivot&quot;&gt;Pivot&lt;/a&gt; and honestly, his phased Medicare expansion idea makes a lot of sense for America. He thinks the path to a national system isn’t some overnight revolution. It’s a slow rollout: cut the Medicare age by two years every two years until it covers everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;65 → 63 → 61 → all the way down to zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple way to move to a real Medicare for All. Hospitals and insurers get time to adjust. People get coverage without waiting for Congress to agree on the perfect plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t agree with Scott on everything he says, but this one strikes me as both practical and humane. &lt;em&gt;Healthcare as a right&lt;/em&gt;, implemented with a plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>